<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-01-19T15:58:07+00:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">Matt Budde</title><subtitle>Blogging about tech and stuff</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Ghost</title><link href="/Blog-Update" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Ghost" /><published>2017-07-27T11:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T11:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/Blog%20Update</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Blog-Update">&lt;h2 id=&quot;blog-update-and-my-first-app-release&quot;&gt;Blog Update and My First App Release&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, it really has been some time since I posted an update here, (around 2 years :S). While it may seem like I have been lazy, I have been working on a few different projects in the background(as well as raising a my 3 year old son :S). The biggest of those is being accepted into the Udacity/Google Front End Web Deveopler Challenge. This has taken up the bulk of my free time the past few months and has really been a great learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.ibb.co/dTZGXR/Capture.png&quot; alt=&quot;App&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of learning I have been mostly working on my just released app &lt;a href=&quot;https://mattbudde.github.io/pomotron-website/&quot;&gt;Pomotron&lt;/a&gt;. It is a fairly simple Pomodoro timer built using HTML, CSS &amp;amp; Javascript using &lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org&quot; title=&quot;Electron&quot;&gt;https://electronjs.org&lt;/a&gt;. There are still many things that can be improved with the app and I am by no means happy with the end result, but better to “finish” something than to have done nothing at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan on going over in more depth what I have learn’t through the Udcaity/Google Challenge as well as sharing some other tools that I have come across while putting together &lt;a href=&quot;https://mattbudde.github.io/pomotron-website/&quot;&gt;Pomotron&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, I am open to suggestions surrounding future topics.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>matt</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html">Blog Update and My First App Release</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Ghost</title><link href="/welcome" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Ghost" /><published>2017-07-27T11:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T11:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="/welcome">&lt;p&gt;Hey! Welcome to Ghost, it’s great to have you :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know that first impressions are important, so we’ve populated your new site with some initial &lt;strong&gt;Getting Started&lt;/strong&gt; posts that will help you get familiar with everything in no time. This is the first one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;there-are-a-few-things-that-you-should-know-up-front&quot;&gt;There are a few things that you should know up-front:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ghost is designed for ambitious, professional publishers who want to actively build a business around their content. That’s who it works best for. If you’re using Ghost for some other purpose, that’s fine too - but it might not be the best choice for you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The entire platform can be modified and customized to suit your needs, which is very powerful, but doing so &lt;strong&gt;does&lt;/strong&gt; require some knowledge of code. Ghost is not necessarily a good platform for beginners or people who just want a simple personal blog.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the best experience we recommend downloading the Ghost Desktop App for your computer, which is the best way to access your Ghost site on a desktop device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ghost is made by an independent non-profit organisation called the Ghost Foundation. We are 100% self funded by revenue from our &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghost.org/pricing&quot;&gt;Ghost(Pro)&lt;/a&gt; service, and every penny we make is re-invested into funding further development of free, open source technology for modern journalism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main thing you’ll want to read about next is probably: &lt;a href=&quot;https://demo.ghost.io/the-editor/&quot;&gt;the Ghost editor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’re done reading, you can simply delete the default &lt;strong&gt;Ghost&lt;/strong&gt; user from your team to remove all of these introductory posts!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ghost</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html">Hey! Welcome to Ghost, it’s great to have you :)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Ghost</title><link href="/Site-Launch" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Ghost" /><published>2017-07-27T11:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T11:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/Site-Launch</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Site-Launch">&lt;h2 id=&quot;welcome&quot;&gt;Welcome&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my homepage dedicated to my random gibberish about tech and development. I am a self taught developer based in Belfast, Northern Ireland. I am currently studying to be a Full Stack Developer using &lt;a href=&quot;https://codermanual.com/&quot;&gt;CoderManual&lt;/a&gt;. You can check out the fruits of this course on my &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/mattbudde&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give an insight into how this self-taught process goes,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;First learn computer science and all the theory. Next develop a programming style. Then forget all that and just hack. - George Carrette&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above sums up the majority of my development process, as showcased by this lovely jekyll theme by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/renyuanz&quot;&gt;Renyuanz&lt;/a&gt;. My aim is obviously, to become a “Full Fledged” developer and eventually turn this into my career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that said, stay tuned for more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>matt</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html">Welcome</summary></entry></feed>